one bonus tip to share
Hello friends
today I am going to share some valuable
tips on buying car insurance also I'm
going to share my own experience with
insurance service provider for Mike Iger
all of us may not be an expert on
insurance however there are a few basic
points we need to keep in mind when
buying car insurance
[Music]
[Applause]
the first thing you need to keep in mind
is whether your car insurance includes
third party liability the motor vehicles
act states that third party liability
insurance is compulsory if you want to
drive a four-wheeler legally on Indian
public roads police officials asks for
insurance they will check whether your
third party liability insurance is
active or not if not then there will be
penalties that you have to face rule is
so strict that you can end up in jail as
well the next thing is to make sure that
your car insurance is a comprehensive
one a comprehensive policy as the name
suggests is a wide-ranging cover it not
only includes the features offered by a
liability only policy but also offers
own damage cover this means you are in
short if your car causes damages to
others and also if it is damaged by
someone else or during natural
calamities
also depending on your needs you can
include add-ons in your car insurance
these can range from zero depreciation
to Roadside Assistance or even engine
cover now let's quickly understand these
add-ons what are they first would be
zero depreciation or zero tap zero depth
would help with doing away with the
insurer charging depreciation when they
are settling claims roadside assistance
this would include the insurance company
providing Services of Towing your
vehicle in the event of breakdown or
accident on the road engine cover this
would cover for charges in case there is
damage or repair done to your car's
engine there are a few more types of
add-ons that you can review and consider
as per your requirement the best way to
pick your car insurance would be to
consider the package consisting of
comprehensive plan plus zero depth plus
add-ons and compare the quotes that you
receive from a few different insurance
companies also consider the insurance
companies online and offline reviews
Plus their overall service performance
it's a service performance I mean what's
their Claims Settlement ratio or
percentage
coming to my personal experience with
car insurance when I bought my car last
year the dealer gave me a decent
insurance package from ICICI Lombard it
was around 35 000. now generally the
cost of insurance is high when you are
initially buying a car and then
gradually comes down as one renews their
own liability insurance from year to
year own liability insurance is valid
for one year and third party insurance
is generally valid for two to three
years
one needs to renew their own liability
insurance each year
my experience with ICICI in Hyderabad
was pathetic I had a few unfortunate
accidents in this one year of insurance
and each time the person from ICICI came
to evaluate the damages and approved the
payout for repairs they kept on doing
mischief
multiple times it happened that this
person refused to conclude that the
damages took place during the same
incident and then I had to make two
separate claims the same day in order to
complete the total repairs at this rate
there were multiple claims made and each
subsequent time ICICI gave me less
payout for my damage claims it means if
they gave 100 money for repairs for the
first time by the time A fifth or sixth
claim was made they paid only for 40 to
50 percent
initially I was made to believe that
ICICI was the best but that was one of
the biggest mistakes I had made
therefore when my ICICI insurance was
about to expire at the end of July this
year I discussed with different people
and changed my car insurance provider to
Liberty
I again took a comprehensive zero dip
policy and it cost me around 14 000.
also the best part is that in the event
I have to get repairs for my car Liberty
will approve it multiple times in a year
without cutting charges like ICICI did
after every claim was approved
if I had some experience good or bad
with Liberty I will definitely share
with you guys later this year one bonus
tip to share
in case you have minor damages to your
car which cost around let's say five to
ten thousand then it's best to do it
from your own pocket or if you can keep
your car in a running condition then
it's best through the repairs next time
together all at once
we are not making any claims in a year
then the next year's renewal you will
get a discount hope this video was
helpful and see you guys soon